# Charles Li

FRONT END WEB DEVELOPER

#### **Details**

Toronto

Canada

647-907-6252

41charlesli@gmail.com

#### Links

Github

LinkedIn

**Portfolio** 

#### **Skills**

HTML & CSS

**SASS** 

JavaScript

**JQuery** 

React

REST APIs

Firebase

Responsive Design

Accessibility

Github

**Paired Programming** 

Scope Management

## **Profile**

I'm a web developer dedicated to building user-friendly, accessible, and responsive websites and applications. As a former elementary teacher with 10 years of experience, I'm adept at working in a collaborative environment with strong skills in communication, time management, problem-solving, and conflict resolution.

I love reading fantasy novels (just finished the Wheel of Time series) and discovering new ramen shops while I'm traveling

## **Employment History**

## Homeroom Teacher, Toronto District School Board, Toronto

2019 - 2022

- Created safe and inclusive classroom space for over 150 students with lessons designed around students equity and inclusion
- Collaborated with administration in annual development of staffing model, creating grade groupings for over 30 educators
- Transitioned 5 teachers to online teaching through sharing of digital tools, lesson plans, and tech support
- Mentored new teachers through co-planning sessions and co-teaching opportunities
- Participated in school improvement committees such as Social/Health and Safety/Tech/Staffing

# Homeroom, French, Phys Ed Teacher, Toronto District School Board, Toronto

2014 - 2019

- Organized and ran events such as Blue Jays school day, French culture night, and concerts for over 500 students and their families
- Coached teams/ran clubs such as the girls/boys basketball, chess, soccer, Dungeons and Dragons, homework, and guitar
- Piloted first inclusive model at school where we transitioned 8 special education students back into homeroom for language and math
- Taught and designed media literacy lessons for 12 deaf and hard of hearing students, grades 4-7

## **Education**

## Front-End Web Development, Juno College, Toronto

JUNE 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2022

**Bachelor of Education, Ontario Institute for Studies in Education, Toronto** 2013

Honours Bachelor of Science, University of Toronto

2008

# **Projects**

Movie Randomizer, HTML | SASS | JS | Local Storage

JUNE 2022

Live Site | Github

Creative PSD conversion, HTML | SASS | JS

JUNE 2022

Live Site | Github